Georg J.P. Link

6001 Dodge Street, PKI 367, Omaha, Nebraska 68182, USA linkgeorg@gmail.com • +1 (402) 206-7635 • http://georg.link/

SUMMARY

My research advances our knowledge in corporate engagement with open source projects. As corporate involvement increases, open source foundations provide guidance and support for open source projects. We only begin to understand the evolution of this triangular relationship. My current research focus is to inform this relationship through research into open source project health and new market mechanisms. My work has been accepted to the Communications of the Association for Information Systems, the Journal for Universal Computer Science, ACM GROUP, Americas Conference on Information Systems, OpenSym, HICSS, CHAOSSCon, INFORMS, and MWAIS. My research has been supported by the Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, Mozilla, and the Linux Foundation.

I am engaged at both professional and university levels. I volunteered at various academic conferences, was a conference co-organizer for the 2017 Big XII+ MIS Symposium, am currently the Communications Chair for AIS SIGOPEN, and am an active member of the University of Nebraska at Omaha's BRIDGE Lab — a lab dedicated to the advancement of IT design, architecture, and education. I have reviewed for ICIS, AMCIS, MWAIS, ECIS, PACIS, HICSS, and OpenSym. Finally, I am an active member in the Linux Foundation CHAOSS project and the Mozilla Bugmark project.

EDUCATION

University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, Nebraska, USA

Ph.D. in Information Technology
 Thesis: Signaling Theory in Collaborative Environments

• Advisor: Prof. Matt Germonprez

• Focus: Open Source Community Health

■ MBA – Master of Business Administration 2013

• Concentration: Collaboration Science

• Cumulative GPA: 3.9 / 4.0

Technical University Braunschweig, Braunschweig, Germany

M.S. in Business Informatics

2014

• Thesis: Evaluating Anchored Discussion as a New Tool for Creativity in Online Collaboration

• Cumulative GPA: 1.3 (German grade translates to 3.7 / 4.0)

WelfenAkademie, Braunschweig, Germany

■ B.A. in Business Administration

2011

• Concentration: Banking

Cumulative GPA: 1.8 (German grade translates to 3.2 / 4.0)

GRANT FUNDING Total: \$8,759.00

■ \$2,441.00 - Mozilla

2018

• Travel support to ACM Collective Intelligence, Zurich, Switzerland

• \$1,318.00 - Linux Foundation

2017

· Travel support to Open Source Summit North America, Los Angeles, CA, USA

• \$5,000.00 - University of Nebraska at Omaha

2017

Program: Graduate Research and Creative Activity (GRACA)

2017

• Proposal title: The Changing Nature of Volunteerism in Open Source Communities

SCHOLARSHIPS

Hanns-Seidel-Stiftung

2012 - 2014

German Academic Exchange Service (DAAD)

2012 - 2013

HONORS & AWARDS

■ Best Paper Award, AIS SIG GlobDev

2017

- Link, G. J.P., & Qureshi, S. (2017). The role of open source in new business formation: Innovations for development. In *Proceedings of the Twenty-third Americas Conference on Information Systems*. Boston.
- Above and Beyond Excellence Award from UNO Student Government

2013

• Rotary Youth Leadership Award (RYLA) Seminar

2008

PUBLICATIONS

JOURNALS

- [2] Link, G. J.P., K. Lumbard, K. Conboy, M. Feldman, J. Feller, J. George, M. Germonprez, S. Goggins, D. Jeske, G. Kiely, K. Schuster, M. Willis (2017). Contemporary issues of open data in Information Systems research: Considerations and recommendations. *Communications of the Association for Information Systems*, *41*(Article 25), 587–610. http://aisel.aisnet.org/cais/vol41/iss1/25/
- [1] Link, G. J.P., D. Siemon, G. de Vreede, S. Robra-Bissantz (2016). Anchored Discussion: Development of a Tool for Creativity in Online Collaboration, *Journal for Universal Computer Science*, 22(10), 1339–1359. https://doi.org/10.3217/jucs-022-10-1339

CONFERENCES

- [13] Link, G. J.P., & Germonprez, M. (2018). Assessing open source project health. In Twenty-fourth Americas Conference on Information Systems 2018 Proceedings. New Orleans, LA.
- [12] Rao, M., Link, G. J.P., Marti, D., Leak, A., & Bodo, R. (2018). A trading market for prices in peer production. In ACM Collective Intelligence 2018 Proceedings. Zurich, Switzerland.
- [11] Rao, M., Link, G. J.P., Marti, D., Leak, A., & Bodo, R. (2018). A Trading Market to Incentivize Secure Software. In 17th Annual Workshop on the Economics of Information Security (WEIS), Innsbruck, Austria.
- [10] Gandhi, R., Germonprez, M., & Link, G. J.P.* (2018). Open data standards for open source software risk management routines: An examination of SPDX. Presented at the ACM GROUP'18, Sanibel Island. https://doi.org/10.1145/3148330.3148333
- [9] <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, & Qureshi, S. (2018). The role of open source communities in development: Policy implications for governments. Presented at the HICSS 2018, Hawaii. http://hdl.handle.net/10125/ 50190
- [8] Link, G. J.P. (2017). The value of engaging with open source communities. In *OpenSym '17 Companion*. Galway, Ireland: ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/3126673.3126679
- [7] <u>Link, G. J.P.,</u> & Jeske, D. (2017). Understanding organization and open source community relations through the Attraction-Selection-Attrition Model. In *OpenSym '17 Companion*. Galway, Ireland: ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/3125433.3125472
- [6] <u>Link, G. J.P.,</u> & Qureshi, S. (2017). The role of open source in new business formation: Innovations for development. In *Proceedings of the Twenty-third Americas Conference on Information Systems*. Boston. Retrieved from http://aisel.aisnet.org/amcis2017/ICTs/Presentations/18/
- [5] <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, Gill, J., & Khazanchi, D. (2017). Measuring adoption of open source software and practices in organizations: A pilot study. In *Proceedings of the Twelfth Midwest Association for Information Systems Conference*. Springfield, IL. Retrieved from http://aisel.aisnet.org/mwais2017/43/
- [4] <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, Lumbard, K., Germonprez, M., & Goggins, S. (2017). Advancing open online community science practice: The open community data exchange. In *Proceedings of the Twelfth Midwest Association for Information Systems Conference*. Springfield, IL. http://aisel.aisnet.org/mwais2017/44
- [3] <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, Germonprez, M., Goggins, S., Hemsley, J., Rand, B., & Squire, M. (2016). The Open Community Data Exchange: Advancing data sharing and discovery in open online community science. In *OpenSym '16 Companion*. Berlin, Germany: ACM. https://doi.org/10.1145/2962132. 2962142
- [2] <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, & Germonprez, M. (2016). Understanding open source communities as complex adaptive systems: A case of the R Project community. In AMCIS 2016 Proceedings. San Diego, CA. Retrieved from http://aisel.aisnet.org/amcis2016/Open/Presentations/7/
- [1] <u>Link, G. J.P.</u>, Siemon, D., de Vreede, G.-J., & Robra-Bissantz, S. (2015). Evaluating Anchored Discussion to Foster Creativity in Online Collaboration. In N. Baloian, Y. Zorian, P. Taslakian, & S. Shoukouryan (Eds.), Collaboration and Technology (pp. 28–44). Springer International Publishing. https://doi.org/10.1007/978-3-319-22747-4_3

^{*}Authors in alphabetical order

PRESENTATIONS

- [13] Link, G. J.P. (2018, March). Engaging Volunteers and Voluntolds in Open Source Projects. Presented at the 10th Annual Research and Creative Activity Fair, University of Nebraska at Omaha, NE, USA. https://digitalcommons.unomaha.edu/srcaf/2018/schedule/148/
- [12] Germonprez, M., & Link, G. J. P. (2017, September). BoF: Community Health Analytics for Open Source. Birds-of-a-Feather presented at the Open Source Summit North America, Los Angeles, California. Retrieved from http://sched.co/BCsP
- [11] Link, G. J.P. (2017, August). Understanding organization and open source community relations through the Attraction-Selection-Attrition Model. Presented at OpenSym 2017, Galway, Ireland.
- [10] Link, G. J.P. (2017, August). The value of engaging with open source communities. Presented at the OpenSym 2017 Doctoral Consortium, Galway, Ireland.
- [9] Link, G. J.P. (2017, August). The role of open source in new business formation: Innovations for development. Presented at the Twenty-third Americas Conference on Information Systems, Boston, MA.
- [8] Link, G. J.P., & Lumbard, K. (2017, May). Advancing open online community science practice: The open community data exchange. Presented at the Twelfth Midwest Association for Information Systems Conference. Springfield, IL.
- [7] Link, G. J.P. (2017, May). Measuring adoption of open source software and practices in organizations: A pilot study. Presented at the Twelfth Midwest Association for Information Systems Conference. Springfield, IL.
- [6] Link, G. J.P. (2016, December). Moving Open Source Communities: How Foundations Onboard Communities. Presented at the SIGOPEN Developmental Workshop at ICIS 2016, Dublin, Ireland.
- [5] Link, G. J.P., & Lumbard, K. (2016, December). Communication Technology Selection in a Young Open Source Community: A Case of the Hyperledger Project. Presented at the SIGOPEN Developmental Workshop at ICIS 2016, Dublin, Ireland.
- [4] Link, G. J.P. (2016, August). The Open Community Data Exchange: Advancing Data Sharing and Discovery in Open Online Community Science. Presented at the OpenSym 2016, Berlin, Germany.
- [3] Link, G. J.P. (2016, April). The Guided Evolution of Open Source Communities. Presented at the 14th Annual BigXII+MISResearchSymposium, Baylor University, Waco, TX, USA.
- [2] Link, G. J.P. (2016, March). The Guided Evolution of Open Source Communities. Presented at the 8th Annual Research and Creative Activity Fair, University of Nebraska at Omaha, NE, USA. http://digitalcommons.unomaha.edu/srcaf/2016/Schedule/56/
- [1] Link, G. J.P. (2015, November). The Movement and Commoditization of Open Source Communities. Presented at the INFORMS Annual Meeting 2015, Philadelphia, PA, USA.

ACADEMIC APPOINTMENTS

University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, Nebraska, USA

• Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant

2015 – present

- Funded by Alfred P. Sloan Foundation
- · Funded by Mozilla

WelfenAkademie, Braunschweig, Germany

Visiting Lecturer for Information Systems

2014 – present

Technical University Braunschweig, Braunschweig, Germany

Research Assistant

2014 - 2015

- Institute of Business Information Systems Information Management Group
- Research and Teaching Assistant

2013 - 2014

 Institute of Operating Systems and Computer Networks Algorithms Group

Research Assistant

2011 - 2012

 Institute of Business Information Systems Decision Support Group

GRANT WRITING EXPERIENCE	NSF: Early-concept Grants for Exploratory Research (EAGER) Title: Securing Critical Software Through Futures Markets; PI: Matt Germonprez; Under review.	2018
	Mozilla Research Grants 2018H1 Title: Experiment on Introducing Project Health Signals and Price Signals in Open Source; PI: Georg	2018 g Link; Under review.
	Mozilla Open Source Experiments Program Title: Experiment for Health Signals in Bugmark; PI: Georg Link; Unfunded Grant Proposal	2018
	Alfred P. Sloan Foundation Title: Open Source Project Health and Sustainability; PI: Matt Germonprez and Sean Goggins; (2018-2020)	2017 Funded with \$449,351
	GRACA internal grant University of Nebraska at Omaha Graduate Research and Creative Activity (GRACA); Title: The Changing Nature of Volunte Communities; PI: Georg Link; Funded with \$5,000 (2017)	2017 eerism in Open source
	GRACA internal grant University of Nebraska at Omaha Graduate Research and Creative Activity (GRACA); Title: The Guided Evolution of Open Source C Link; Unfunded proposal.	2016 Communities; PI: Georg
	BMBF (German Federal Ministry of Education and Research) Title: DETHIS - Design Thinking for Industrial Services; PI: Christoph Lattemann; Project number 1.6 million Euro (2016-2019).	2014 01FJ15100 funded with
TEACHING EXPERIENCE	Managing the Database Environment University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, Nebraska, USA	2017 – 2018
	Organizations, Applications, and Technology University of Nebraska at Omaha, Omaha, Nebraska, USA	2017
	Introduction to Microsoft Excel WelfenAkademie, Braunschweig, Germany	2014 – Present
PROFESSIONAL	UNO Mozilla Campus Club, University of Nebraska at Omaha	
UNIVERSITY ACTIVITIES	■ Founder and Vice-President	2018 – Present
	Graduate College Committee , University of Nebraska at Omaha	
	■ Student Representative	2016 – 2018
	UCRCA Committee (internal grants), University of Nebraska at Omaha	
	■ Student Representative	2016 – 2017
	PhD Student Group, University of Nebraska at Omaha	
	■ Founder and President	2015 – 2017
PROFESSIONAL	Executive	
ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES	 Communications Director, AIS SIGOPEN 	2015 – Present
	 Organizing (Conference and Workshop) OpenSym Program Committee AMCIS Minitrack Co-Chair Minitrack: Peer Production Project Health 	2018 2018
	OpenSym Program Committee and Session ChairSIGOPEN Pre-ICIS Workshop on Open Phenomena	2017 2017
	Reviewing for Journals 2018 Information and Organization Information Technology for Development Journal of Organizational Computing and Electronic Commerce	2018
	 2017 Information Technology for Development Information & Management International Journal of Entrepreneurship and Small Business International Journal of Human-Computer Interaction 	2017

• International Journal of Human-Computer Interaction

	2016Communications of the Association for Information Systems	2016
	Reviewing for Conferences 2018: ICIS, AMCIS, OpenSym 2017: AMCIS, ECIS, PACIS, MWAIS, OpenSym 2016: ICIS, HICSS, AMCIS, ECIS 2015: ECIS	2018 2017 2016 2015
	 Conference Volunteering ACM Group OpenSym Big XII+ MIS Research Symposium International Conference on Information Systems International Conference on Web Intelligence and International Conference on Brain Informatics & Health Coalition of Urban and Metropolitan Universities 	2018 2017 2017 2016 2016 2015
PROFESSIONAL AFFILIATIONS	Association for Information Systems (AIS) AIS SIGOPEN Midwest United States Association for Information Systems (MWAIS)	2016 – Present
	Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)	2016 – Present
INDUSTRY TRAINING & CERTIFICATES	 Bankkaufmann Certified by Chamber of Commerce, Braunschweig, Germany Bankhaus C. L. Seeliger, Wolfenbüttel, Germany 	2008 – 2011
	Ausbilder-Eignungsprüfung	2011
	Certified by Chamber of Commerce, Braunschweig, GermanyWelfenAkademie, Braunschweig, Germany	
REFERENCES	 Matt Germonprez Mutual of Omaha Associate Professor Information Systems and Quantitative Analysis University of Nebraska at Omaha mgermonprez@unomaha.edu 	
	 Sean Goggins Associate Professor School of Information Science and Learning Technologies University of Missouri s@goggins.com 	
	 Brian Dorn Associate Professor Computer Science University of Nebraska at Omaha bdorn@unomaha.edu 	
	Robin A. Gandhi Associate Professor Cybersecurity University of Nebraska at Omaha rgandhi@unomaha.edu	

[CV last updated on 2018-05-18]

